<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Scicloj</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</guid><description>What #
Scicloj is an open, free and dynamic hub for building a Clojure ecosystem for data science, scientific computing and data engineering.
In short, it is for anyone who is interested in using Clojure to work with data.
There are various places where activities move forward (for more info check the Where section), and they are all open to discussion and contribution.
Who #
We are Clojurians coming from very different backgrounds and with very different levels of knowledge around Clojure and data science who share a common goal: making Clojure and data science better by combining them.</description></item><item><title>Getting Involved</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</guid><description>Would you like to join our journey in making Clojure a joyful platform for data science?
Below are some suggested ways to get involved. If you are interested in any of these, or maybe have some other idea - then let us talk! We may possibly help in finding a nice way to begin.
Let us talk
Join our Open Source Mentoring program #
Our Open Source Mentoring program offers a clear path to becoming a contributor on Scicloj open source projects.</description></item><item><title>Chat</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</guid><description>The Clojurians Zulip #
Most of our communication takes place in specific streams (also called channels) at the Clojurians Zulip chat.
Small task groups often create ad-hoc streams for their task, but a lot of the communitcation takes place in more popular, long-living streams (examples below).
Most streams are public, some are private. Usually, streams are chosen to be private not for secrecy, but for focus, and for creating an atmosphere where people are comfortable talking, knowing who are listening.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/events/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/events/</guid><description>Our public events are shared at the Clojure calendar feed and at the various Clojure social platforms
You are encouaged to add the feed to your calendar and follow look into it through the online viewer.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</guid><description> scicloj@gmail.com GitHub Zulip Chat streams Main data science stream Youtube</description></item></channel></rss>