<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>daslu on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/contributors/daslu/</link><description>Recent content in daslu on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/contributors/daslu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Following our first five LLM meetups</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/following-our-first-five-llm-meetups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/following-our-first-five-llm-meetups/</guid><description>In May 2023, Scicloj started organizing a series of meetups around Large Language Models.
This series was inpired by a few other projects in the Clojure community, such as Rupert&amp;rsquo;s initiative to work on models that may work well with Clojure language tasks, the related #clojurellm channel that was created by John Newman and Rupert, and the various libraries for LLMs and related services, that have been keep emerging mostly during 2023.</description></item><item><title>About Scicloj</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</guid><description>What #
Scicloj is an open, free and dynamic hub for building a Clojure ecosystem for data science, scientific computing and data engineering.
In short, it is for anyone who is interested in using Clojure to work with data.
There are various places where activities move forward (for more info check the Where section), and they are all open to discussion and contribution.
Who #
We are Clojurians coming from very different backgrounds and with very different levels of knowledge around Clojure and data science who share a common goal: making Clojure and data science better by combining them.</description></item><item><title>Getting Involved</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</guid><description>Would you like to join our journey in making Clojure a joyful platform for data science?
Below are some suggested ways to get involved. If you are interested in any of these, or maybe have some other idea - then let us talk! We may possibly help in finding a nice way to begin.
Join our dev and study groups #
Scicloj is organizing a few dev groups and study groups that meet regularly to learn, to brainstorm, and to create.</description></item><item><title>Chat streams</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</guid><description>The Clojurians Zulip #
Most of our communication takes place in specific streams at the Clojurians Zulip chat.
Small task groups often create ad-hoc streams for their task, but a lot of the communitcation takes place in more popular, long-living streams (examples below).
Most streams are public, some are private. Usually, streams are chosen to be private not for secrecy, but for focus, and for creating an atmosphere where people are comfortable talking, knowing who are listening.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</guid><description> scicloj@gmail.com GitHub Zulip Chat streams Main data science stream Twitter Youtube</description></item><item><title>Jointprob community updates - Probability Basics talk, Hierarchical Models followup</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/jointprob-community-updates-probability-basics-talk-hierarchical-models-followup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/jointprob-community-updates-probability-basics-talk-hierarchical-models-followup/</guid><description>⭐ TL;DR: See you at the September standalone talk of the Jointprob &amp;ndash; an intro to Probability basics. Also, please check out 🎥 the recording of the August talk by David MacGillivray about Bayesian Hierarchical Models. ⭐
Background #
The Jointprob community was created by Scicloj during the summer of 2022, aspiring to be a space where friends of diverse backgrounds can learn &amp;amp; explore Bayesian statistics and probabilistic modeling.</description></item><item><title>Tools and libraries</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/libs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/libs/</guid><description>To supplement our opinionated discussions of the ecosystem, here is a less-opinionated, plain list of relevant libraries written by Clojurians. Not all libraries mentioned here are affiliated with Scicloj, but we seek to be in dialogue with library authors as much as possible.
Do you know about anything relevant that is missing here? - Let us talk!
For every library, we mark whether it is actively developed (act), and whether it is still experimental (exp).</description></item><item><title>Reading</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/reading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/reading/</guid><description>Here are some suggested reading materials.
Do you wish to add your tutorial to this list? Do you have any suggestions for this list? - Let us talk!
Scicloj resources #
The Clojure Data Scrapbook - a community-driven collection of tutorials for the emerging Clojure data stack - contributions are welcome. 🙏 Blogs #
TechAscent Blog by the group behind a few of the Clojure high-performance and data-analytics libraries (mostly those at techascent, as well as dtype-next and libpython-clj)</description></item><item><title>Video</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/video/</guid><description>Clojure Data Scrapbook accompanying videos #
2024-03-30 - Noj - getting started - from raw data to a blog post Clojure/Conj 2023 #
A few of the Clojure/Conj talks were dedicated to infrastructure and applications of the emerging Clojure data science stack.
&amp;ldquo;Vector Symbolic Architectures In Clojure&amp;rdquo; by Carin Meier &amp;ldquo;High Performance Clojure&amp;rdquo; by Chris Nuernberger &amp;ldquo;Clojure in the Fintech Ecosystem&amp;rdquo; by Philip Cooper &amp;ldquo;Real @toms with Clojure!</description></item><item><title>Audio</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/audio/</guid><description>Recommended podcast conversations
ClojureStream #
E72 Data Processing with Chris Nuernberger (part 1)
E73 Data Processing with Chris Nuernberger (part 2)
E74 Linear Algebra with David Pham
E78 Data Science with Daniel Slutsky
Cognicast #
2017-05-31 Episode 125 - Chris Nuernberger: deep learning (from the times of Cortex)
2020-06-29 Episode 153 - Chris Nuernberger: [Libpython-clj](, etc.), etc.
2020-10-25 Episode 154 - Dragan Djuric: deep learning, etc.
defn #
#86 Kira McLean</description></item></channel></rss>