<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>daslu on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/contributors/daslu/</link><description>Recent content in daslu on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/contributors/daslu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Scicloj</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</guid><description>What #
Scicloj is an open, free and dynamic hub for building a Clojure ecosystem for data science, scientific computing and data engineering.
In short, it is for anyone who is interested in using Clojure to work with data.
There are various places where activities move forward (for more info check the Where section), and they are all open to discussion and contribution.
Who #
We are Clojurians coming from very different backgrounds and with very different levels of knowledge around Clojure and data science who share a common goal: making Clojure and data science better by combining them.</description></item><item><title>Getting Involved</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</guid><description>Would you like to join our journey in making Clojure a joyful platform for data science?
Below are some suggested ways to get involved. If you are interested in any of these, or maybe have some other idea - then let us talk! We may possibly help in finding a nice way to begin.
Join our dev and study groups #
Scicloj is organizing a few dev groups and study groups that meet regularly to learn, to brainstorm, and to create.</description></item><item><title>Chat streams</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</guid><description>The Clojurians Zulip #
Most of our communication takes place in specific streams at the Clojurians Zulip chat.
Small task groups often create ad-hoc streams for their task, but a lot of the communitcation takes place in more popular, long-living streams (examples below).
Most streams are public, some are private. Usually, streams are chosen to be private not for secrecy, but for focus, and for creating an atmosphere where people are comfortable talking, knowing who are listening.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</guid><description> scicloj@gmail.com GitHub Zulip Chat streams Main data science stream Twitter Youtube</description></item><item><title>Tools and libraries</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/libs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/libs/</guid><description>To supplement our opinionated discussions of the ecosystem, here is a less-opinionated, plain list of relevant libraries written by Clojurians. Not all libraries mentioned here are affiliated with Scicloj, but we seek to be in dialogue with library authors as much as possible.
Do you know about anything relevant that is missing here? - Let us talk!
For every library, we mark whether it is actively developed (act), and whether it is still experimental (exp).</description></item><item><title>Reading</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/reading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/reading/</guid><description>Here are some suggested reading materials.
Do you wish to add your tutorial to this list? Do you have any suggestions for this list? - Let us talk!
Blogs #
TechAscent Blog by the group behind a few of the Clojure high-performance and data-analytics libraries (mostly those at techascent, as well as dtype-next and libpython-clj)
Squid&amp;rsquo;s Blogs by Carin Meier - deep learning, MXNet, Python interop and other technical topics</description></item><item><title>Video</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/video/</guid><description>re:Clojure 2021 #
Scicloj joined the London Clojurians in organizing the re:Clojure 2021 event and its workshops - ⭐ The following playlists are recommended as an up-to-date look into a few parts of the emerging data-science stack. ⭐
Dec. 5th, re:Clojure 2021 Data Science Special - playlist Dec. 3rd-4th, re:Clojure 2021 Conference - playlist Nov., re:Clojure 2021 Workshops - playlist Interviews #
June 30th, 5pm UTC - Jon Anthony interviewed about Hanami &amp;amp; Saite by Alan Marazzi, Ethan Zane Miller and Vijay Kiran - video April 26th - Chris Nuernberger interviewed by Teodor Heggelund, Tomasz Sulej and Daniel Slutsky - video September 27th - Anthony Khong interviewed by Vijay Kiran, Teodor Heggelund and Daniel Slutsky about Geni - video Public sessions of dev &amp;amp; study groups #
ds4clj #
As of Fall 2022, the planned Data Science for Clojure devs course is delayed.</description></item><item><title>The Jointprob community: changes on the agenda, and an upcoming talk about Bayesian Hierarchical Models</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/the-jointprob-community-changes-on-the-agenda-and-an-upcoming-talk-about-bayesian-hierarchical-models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/the-jointprob-community-changes-on-the-agenda-and-an-upcoming-talk-about-bayesian-hierarchical-models/</guid><description>⭐ TL;DR: In the coming weeks and months, the Jointprob community will organize standalone talks about topics in Bayesian Statistics and Probabilistic Modeling. The first one will be in August, by David MacGillivray, about Bayesian Hierarchical Models. ⭐
The Jointprob community was created by Scicloj during the summer of 2022, aspiring to be a space where friends of diverse backgrounds can learn &amp;amp; explore Bayesian statistics and probabilistic modeling.</description></item><item><title>Jointprob in 2023, Bayesian Modeling and Computation, meeting Ravin Kumar</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/jointprob-in-2023-bayesian-modeling-and-computation-meeting-ravin-kumar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/jointprob-in-2023-bayesian-modeling-and-computation-meeting-ravin-kumar/</guid><description>The Jointprob community was created by Scicloj during the summer of 2022, aspiring to be a space where friends of diverse backgrounds can learn &amp;amp; explore Bayesian statistics and probabilistic modeling. In this post, we reflect upon our joint path and announce:
⭐ a new reading journey, and
⭐ a special event with Ravin Kumar, one of the book authors.
If you are curious about any of that, you are encouraged to Join Jointprob.</description></item><item><title>Hello 👋</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/hello/</guid><description>A few informative posts are coming soon, to help in clarifying the situation of the emerging Clojure data-centric stack.</description></item></channel></rss>