<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>daslu on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/contributors/daslu/</link><description>Recent content in daslu on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/contributors/daslu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clojurists Together project - Scicloj community building - September 2024 update</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-september-2024-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-september-2024-update/</guid><description>The Clojurists Together organisation has decided to sponsor Scicloj community building for Q3 2024, as a project by Daniel Slutsky. This is the second time the project is selected this year. Here is Daniel&amp;rsquo;s update for September.
Comments and ideas would help. 🙏
Clojurists Together update - April 2024 - Daniel Slutsky #
Scicloj is a Clojure group developing a stack of tools and libraries for data science. Alongside the technical challenges, community building has been an essential part of its efforts since the beginning of 2019.</description></item><item><title>Clojurists Together project - Scicloj community building - April 2024 update</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-april-2024-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-april-2024-update/</guid><description>The Clojurists Together organisation has decided to sponsor Scicloj community building for Q1 2024, as a project by Daniel Slutsky. The project is taking place in February, March, and April 2024. Here is Daniel&amp;rsquo;s update for April.
Here are the previous ones: Feb 2024, Mar 2024
Comments and ideas would help. 🙏
Clojurists Together update - April 2024 - Daniel Slutsky #
April 2024 was the last of three months on the Clojurists Together project titled &amp;ldquo;Scicloj Community Building and Infrastructure&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Clojurists Together project - Scicloj community building - March 2024 update</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-march-2024-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-march-2024-update/</guid><description>The Clojurists Together organisation has decided to sponsor Scicloj community building for Q1 2024, as a project by Daniel Slutsky. The project is taking place in February, March, and April 2024. Here is Daniel&amp;rsquo;s update for March.
You may see the previous one - the February update - here.
Comments and ideas would help. 🙏
Clojurists Together update - March 2024 - Daniel Slutsky #
March 2024 was the second of three months on the Clojurists Together project titled &amp;ldquo;Scicloj Community Building and Infrastructure&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Clojurists Together project - Scicloj community building - February 2024 update</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-february-2024-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/clojurists-together-project-scicloj-community-building-february-2024-update/</guid><description>The Clojurists Together organisation has decided to sponsor Scicloj community building for Q1 2024, as a project by Daniel Slutsky. The project is taking place in February, March, and April 2024. Here is Daniel&amp;rsquo;s update for February.
Comments and ideas would help. 🙏
Clojurists Together update - February 2024 - Daniel Slutsky #
February 2024 was the first of three months on the Clojurists Together project titled &amp;ldquo;Scicloj Community Building and Infrastructure&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Following our first five LLM meetups</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/following-our-first-five-llm-meetups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/following-our-first-five-llm-meetups/</guid><description>In May 2023, Scicloj started organizing a series of meetups around Large Language Models.
This series was inpired by a few other projects in the Clojure community, such as Rupert&amp;rsquo;s initiative to work on models that may work well with Clojure language tasks, the related #clojurellm channel that was created by John Newman and Rupert, and the various libraries for LLMs and related services, that have been keep emerging mostly during 2023.</description></item><item><title>About Scicloj</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/about/</guid><description>What #
Scicloj is an open, free and dynamic hub for building a Clojure ecosystem for data science, scientific computing and data engineering.
In short, it is for anyone who is interested in using Clojure to work with data.
There are various places where activities move forward (for more info check the Where section), and they are all open to discussion and contribution.
Who #
We are Clojurians coming from very different backgrounds and with very different levels of knowledge around Clojure and data science who share a common goal: making Clojure and data science better by combining them.</description></item><item><title>Getting Involved</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/getting_involved/</guid><description>Would you like to join our journey in making Clojure a joyful platform for data science?
Below are some suggested ways to get involved. If you are interested in any of these, or maybe have some other idea - then let us talk! We may possibly help in finding a nice way to begin.
Let us talk
Join our Open Source Mentoring program #
Our Open Source Mentoring program offers a clear path to becoming a contributor on Scicloj open source projects.</description></item><item><title>Chat streams</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/chat/</guid><description>The Clojurians Zulip #
Most of our communication takes place in specific streams (also called channels) at the Clojurians Zulip chat.
Small task groups often create ad-hoc streams for their task, but a lot of the communitcation takes place in more popular, long-living streams (examples below).
Most streams are public, some are private. Usually, streams are chosen to be private not for secrecy, but for focus, and for creating an atmosphere where people are comfortable talking, knowing who are listening.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/events/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/events/</guid><description>Our public events are shared at the Clojure calendar feed.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/contact/</guid><description> scicloj@gmail.com GitHub Zulip Chat streams Main data science stream Twitter Youtube</description></item></channel></rss>