<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jointprob in 2023, Bayesian Modeling and Computation, meeting Ravin Kumar</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/jointprob-in-2023-bayesian-modeling-and-computation-meeting-ravin-kumar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/jointprob-in-2023-bayesian-modeling-and-computation-meeting-ravin-kumar/</guid><description>The Jointprob community was created by Scicloj during the summer of 2023, aspiring to be a space where friends of diverse backgrounds can learn &amp;amp; explore Bayesian statistics and probabilistic modeling. In this post, we reflect upon our joint path and announce:
⭐ a new reading journey, and
⭐ a special event with Ravin Kumar, one of the book authors.
If you are curious about any of that, you are encouraged to Join Jointprob.</description></item><item><title>Predict real vs. fake disaster tweets</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/predict-real-vs.-fake-disaster-tweets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/predict-real-vs.-fake-disaster-tweets/</guid><description>Any a little bit more serious machine learning, like participating in a Kaggle competition, requires in my view a form of ML experiment tracking.
As ML requires a lot of different trying of code, models and hyper-parameters, we need to have a tools which keeps track of this.
These type of tools can be programming language independent, as they see the code (whatever code) such as one of the assets to track (among hyper-parameters, performance metrics and data)</description></item><item><title>Hello 👋</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/hello/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/blog/hello/</guid><description>A few informative posts are coming soon, to help in clarifying the situation of the emerging Clojure data-centric stack.</description></item></channel></rss>