<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dev &amp; study groups on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/</link><description>Recent content in Dev &amp; study groups on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>{on hold} ds4clj: a data science course for Clojure devs</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/ds4clj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/ds4clj/</guid><description>Following broad support on Clojureverse and Reddit conversations and elsewhere, we have been planning a data-science course for Clojure devs during 2023. For various reasons of community priorities, this project was delayed. As of May 2024, we are reconsidering a revised version, which is probably a semi-structured series of talks alongside the more hands-on real-world-data group.
The content below is the old 2022-2023 draft.
exploration meetings preparing for the course #
2022-07-24, initial brainstorming - event 2022-08-06, prep meeting about R &amp;amp; Tidyverse - event 2022-09-10, NLP study session 1 - summary &amp;amp; video 2022-10-30, NLP study session 2: Predict real vs.</description></item><item><title>scicloj-ai-meetups: exploring the princples and uses of AI models</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/ai-meetups/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/ai-meetups/</guid><description>📣 Coming on Feb. 22 2025.
📅Follow our meetings on the Clojure Calendar Feed📅
The goal of this series of meetups is to support our learning, as a community, of the landscape of ideas around AI models. It continues the journey of the scicloj-llm-meetups group and broandens the scope to various AI models, their principles, and applications.
Some of the content here is specific to the Clojure ecosystem, but many parts of it will be helpful and interesting to broader audiences.</description></item><item><title>SciNoj Light: an online conference for Clojure data-analysis stories</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/scinoj-light/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/scinoj-light/</guid><description>In recent months, the Clojure toolkit for data and science has been maturing. Thus, in 2025, Scicloj can finally shift more resources into making it accessible and well-known.
SciNoj Light is one of the first steps in that direction.
📆 Event (also available at the Clojure Calendar Feed)
What is it #
SciNoj Light is an online conference where Clojurians will share their short-term data analysis stories.
Goals #
Encourage Clojurians to create small-but-complete usage stories of Noj and related libraries.</description></item><item><title>Scicloj open-source mentoring</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/open-source-mentoring/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/open-source-mentoring/</guid><description>Scicloj offers mentoring to Clojurians who wish to become active in open-source projects.
Please reach out
What is that? #
One of the big challenges of getting involved in open source is gaining a sense of relevance: are the features you are working on actually valuable? That is one of the main benefits of collaborating with open-source groups such as Scicloj.
Scicloj offers a clear path to getting involved in open-source tools and libraries, both new and established.</description></item><item><title>{coming soon} a dev group about interop and transpilers</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/interop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/interop/</guid><description>coming soon
In this group, we wish to explore projects such as ClojisR&amp;rsquo;s code generation, a similar layer we have at Wolframite, and general transpilers such as Kalai and Std.lang.
We hope to find some common ground and principles across these projects.
As of May 2024, we are not organizing this group yet, but hopefully it will begin later during this year.</description></item><item><title>data-recur: recurring updates &amp; discussions around building the emerging data stack</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/data-recur/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/data-recur/</guid><description>This group is a space for recurring updates &amp;amp; discussions around the emerging Clojure stack for data processing, analysis, and visualization.
Future meetings #
The R4Clj series meeting will continue roughly every two weeks. Past meetings #
2025-01-31 - meeting 7 - R4Clj 1: Introducing R and the Tidyverse - 🎥 summary &amp;amp; recording 2024-08-08 - meeting 6: Clojure Meets Metal: Working with native libraries and the GPU - 🎥 summary &amp;amp; recording 2024-06-29 - meeting 5: Datajure - 🎥 summary &amp;amp; recording 2022-11-05 - meeting 4: Tablecloth - 🎥 summary &amp;amp; recording 2022-09-30 - meeting 3: Meander - 🎥 sumamry &amp;amp; video 2022-08-27 - meeting 2: Clojask, columns for Tablecloth, ds4clj, and more - 🎥 summary &amp;amp; recording 2022-07-29 - meeting 1: clojure.</description></item><item><title>{renamed} scicloj-llm-meetups: public meetings exploring the princples and use of large language models</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/llm-meetups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/llm-meetups/</guid><description>📣 This 2023 group is being continued as the scicloj-ai-meetups group, starting Feb. 2025.
The goal of this series of meetups is to support our learning, as a community, of the new landscape of ideas around large language models.
Some of the content here is specific to the Clojure ecosystem (e.g., discussing the use of LLMs from Clojure), but many parts of it could be helpful and interesting to broader audiences.</description></item><item><title>{on hold} Jointprob: a probabilistic modeling and Bayesian statistics study community</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/jointprob/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/jointprob/</guid><description>Jointprob is a study community for probabilistic modeling and Bayesian statistics, running since August 2022.
Even though the community was initiated by Scicloj &amp;ndash; a community for data science in Clojure &amp;ndash; this study community is not focused on any single technology or programming language. Rather, it is open to people of diverse technical backgrounds and will continually seek dialogue and mutual inspiration across languages and technologies.</description></item><item><title>{renamed} probabilistic modelling study group</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/probabilistic-modelling-study-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/probabilistic-modelling-study-group/</guid><description>This group has been renamed as jointprob.</description></item><item><title>real-world-data: a space to discuss your data and science projects in Clojure</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/real-world-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/real-world-data/</guid><description>The real-world-data group is about the use of Clojure for data and science problems.
Schedule #
The group meets regularly every second Friday, 17:00 UTC time zone. Please let us know if you wish to join but the time does not work. We may adjust it.
Feb 21th, 2025 - meeting 25 - agenda: Preparation for [SciNoj Light](https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/scinoj-light/ Feb 7th, 2025 - meeting 24 - agenda: details in Zulip chat - 📆 event Jan 24th, 2025 - meeting 23 - agenda: learning R and the tidyverse Jan 10th, 2025 - meeting 22 - agenda: community building, exploring the datatypes of array-programming libraries Dec 21th, 2024 - meeting 21 - agenda: numerical linear algebra - 📖worked on this draft Dec 13th, 2024 - meeting 20 - (details in Zulip chat) Nov 29th, 2024 - meeting 19 - agenda: updates and discussion (details in Zulip chat) Nov 15th, 2024 - meeting 18 - agenda: Library plans - composing Fastmath with Tablecloth Nov 1st, 2024 - meeting 17 - agenda: Noj tutorials (details in Zulip chat) Oct 18th, 2024 - meeting 16 - agenda: diverse updates (details in Zulip chat) - publicly shared recording: 🎥 Jarkko Saltiola: tools for pipelines, bb-glitchtip Oct 4th, 2024 - meeting 15 - agenda: diverse updates (details in Zulip chat) - publicly shared redordings: 🎥 Kyle Passarelli: OAuth2 with Clojure and Temporal 🎥 Adham Omram: Experience Conducting a Clojure Training Sep 20th, 2024 - meeting 14 - agenda: diving into libraries (details in Zulip chat) Sep 6th, 2024 - meeting 13 - agenda: Heart-of-Clojure pre-discussions, clojure-data-tutorials, library updates Aug 23th, 2024 - meeting 12 - agenda: diverse updates (details in Zulip chat) - publicly shared recordings: 🎥 Blender &amp;amp; Basilisp, Wordpress &amp;amp; Phel - Jarkko Saltiola 🎥 Noj, open-source-mentoring - Daniel Slutsky Aug 9th, 2024 - meeting 11 - agenda: diverse updates (details in Zulip chat) July 26th, 2024 - meeting 10 - agenda: diverse updates (details in Zulip chat) July 12th, 2024 - meeting 9 - agenda: diverse updates (details in Zulip chat) June 28th, 2024 - meeting 8 - topic: high-performance numerics (cont.</description></item></channel></rss>