<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dev &amp; study groups on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/</link><description>Recent content in Dev &amp; study groups on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Probabilistic-modelling-study-group</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/probabilistic-modelling-study-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/probabilistic-modelling-study-group/</guid><description>This page describes the emerging plans for a new online study group in Fall 2022, around the topics of probabilistic modelling and Bayesian computing.
Even though the group is initiated by Scicloj &amp;ndash; a community for data science in Clojure &amp;ndash; this study group will not be focused on any single technology or programming language. Rather, it will be open to people of diverse technical backgrounds, and will continually seek dialogue and mutual inspiration across languages and technologies.</description></item><item><title>ml-study</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/ml-study/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/ml-study/</guid><description>(this group is on hold, as of Feb. 2022 &amp;ndash; hoping to come back in the near future)
The ml-study group has been a space for regular meetings about practicing the usage of the emerging Clojure data science stack.
It has been serving us not only in learning, but also in testing the emerging stack and creating a collection of usage examples.
Organizer: Daniel Slutsky (please reach out at the Clojurians Zulip)</description></item><item><title>real-world-data</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/real-world-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/real-world-data/</guid><description>The real-world-data group is about the use of Clojure for real-world data problems.
The goal is to create a space where individuals, companies, academic groups, and organizations are able to share their experiences in using Clojure for data-centric projects. Data analytics, machine learning, AI, data engineering, scientific computing, and data visualization are all welcome.
We want it to be a safe space, that would be comfortable for sharing successes, troubles, problems, hopes, and doubts.</description></item><item><title>sci-fu</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/sci-fu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/sci-fu/</guid><description>(this group is on hold, as of Feb. 2022 &amp;ndash; hoping to come back in the near future)
The sci-fu (Scicloj foundations) has been a space for regular discussions of various dev projects.
In a sense, it is a study group where we learn how to contribute to the ecosystem &amp;ndash; For a few of us, sci-fu has been a place to discuss our first steps as open-source contributors.
In another sense, it is a dev group where we discuss common priorities, share our progress and challenges, and explore future directions.</description></item><item><title>sicmutils</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/sicmutils/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/sicmutils/</guid><description>The sicmutils group has been studying the Sicmutils computer algebra system and the SICM book, and discussing various projects by group members around the topics of math and physics in Clojure.
Its exploration have affected the development of some of our tools and libraries for data-visualization and literate programming, among other things.
Organizer: Daniel Slutsky (please reach out at the Clojurians Zulip)
Typical time of meetings: ad hoc meetings by group members' initiatives</description></item><item><title>visual-tools</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/visual-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/visual-tools/</guid><description>The goal of the group is to create collaborations around learning and building Clojure tools for data visualization and literate programming.
The authors of several actively developed tools are involved (Chlorine, Clover, Calva, Portal, Viscous, Sidebar, Nette, Fabricate, Omni-trace, Oz, Saite, Notespace, Clay, Goldly, Saturn, clt-tiles, Obsidian Wielder, Cardigan Bay, Platypub, etc.).
Meeting 1 - the beginning (Feb. 4th 2022) - summary &amp;amp; video. Meeting 2 - compatibility across tools (Feb.</description></item><item><title>wolfram-clojure-bridge</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/wolfram-clojure-bridge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/community/groups/wolfram-clojure-bridge/</guid><description>The wolfram-clojure-bridge discusses the usage and development of the bridge to Wolfram Language.
When we meet, we spend the time with overviews of new developments, discussion of language design and library design, and explorations of the Wolfram Language ecosystem.
For more background about the project, please see the Dec. 5th 2021 talk of the maintainer, Pawel Ceranka.
Organizer: Pawel Ceranka (please reach out to prnc at the Clojurians Zulip)
Time of meetings: Last Thurdsday of every month, at 18:00 UTC</description></item></channel></rss>