<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tools and libraries</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/libs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/libs/</guid><description>To supplement our opinionated blog posts analysing the ecosystem, here is a less-opinionated, plain list of relevant libraries written by Clojurians. Not all libraries mentioned here are affiliated with Scicloj, but we seek to be in dialogue with library authors as much as possible.
Do you know about anything relevant that is missing here? - Let us talk!
For every library, we mark whether it is actively developed (act), and whether it is still experimental (exp).</description></item><item><title>Reading</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/reading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/reading/</guid><description>Here are some suggested reading materials.
Do you wish to add your tutorial to this list? Do you have any suggestions for this list? - Let us talk!
Blogs #
Squid&amp;rsquo;s Blogs by Carin Meier - deep learning, MXNet, Python interop and other technical topics
Arthur Caillau&amp;rsquo;s Blog - featuring the &amp;ldquo;MXNet made simple&amp;rdquo; series
Dragan Djuric - numerical computing, linear algebra, high performance computing and deep learning</description></item><item><title>video</title><link>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicloj.github.io/docs/resources/video/</guid><description>re:Clojure 2021 #
Scicloj joined the London Clojurians in organizing the re:Clojure 2021 event and its workshops.
Dec. 5th, re:Clojure 2021 Data Science Special - playlist Dec. 3rd-4th, re:Clojure 2021 Conference - playlist Nov., re:Clojure 2021 Workshops - playlist Interviews #
June 30th, 5pm UTC - Jon Anthony interviewed about Hanami &amp;amp; Saite by Alan Marazzi, Ethan Zane Miller and Vijay Kiran - video April 26th - Chris Nuernberger interviewed by Teodor Heggelund, Tomasz Sulej and Daniel Slutsky - video September 27th - Anthony Khong interviewed by Vijay Kiran, Teodor Heggelund and Daniel Slutsky about Geni - video Public sessions of dev &amp;amp; study groups #
visual-tools #
The visual tools group is about creating collaborations across differnent tooling projects for data visualization and literate programming.</description></item></channel></rss>